[
    {
        "question": "Which bank has launched its first Cybersecurity Hackathon 2024-25, with the theme Code Against Malware?",
        "options": [
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "Bank of India  ",
            "Bank of Baroda  ",
            "Punjab National Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Punjab National Bank ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which javelin thrower has been named as the best javelin athlete of 2024 by the American Magazine Track and Field News?",
        "options": [
            "Anderson Peters ",
            "Neeraj Chopra ",
            "Arshad Nadeem ",
            "Julian Weber "
        ],
        "answer": "Neeraj Chopra ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has become the fastest Indian woman to reach 4,000 runs in international cricket?",
        "options": [
            "Smriti Mandhana ",
            "Mithali Raj ",
            "Shafali Verma ",
            "Harmanpreet Kaur "
        ],
        "answer": "Smriti Mandhana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government has inaugurated Maa Ki Rasoi offering full meal for just Rs 9?",
        "options": [
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Bihar  ",
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Jharkhand "
        ],
        "answer": "Uttar Pradesh  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which financial institutions has approved a $35 million project to support over 5 lakh adolescents in Meghalaya by addressing key challenges in education, health and skill development?",
        "options": [
            "Asian Development Bank (ADB) ",
            "Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank (AIIB)  ",
            "International Monetary Fund (IMF)  D) World Bank (WB) "
        ],
        "answer": "Unknown",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Karakoram Wildlife Sanctuary, which was seen in the news, is located in which state/UT?",
        "options": [
            "Jammu and Kashmir  ",
            "Ladakh  ",
            "Himachal Pradesh  ",
            "Uttarakhand "
        ],
        "answer": "Ladakh  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which IT company has partnered with Andhra Pradesh to enhance employment opportunities through a skill census program?",
        "options": [
            "Tata Consultancy Services ",
            "Infosys ",
            "HCL Technologies ",
            "Wipro "
        ],
        "answer": "Infosys ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "India and Singapore are celebrating their________ anniversary of diplomatic relations this year with a series of high-level visits.",
        "options": [
            "60th ",
            "55th ",
            "86th ",
            "74th "
        ],
        "answer": "60th ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prime Minister Narendra Modi will be attending the Artificial Intelligence (AI) Action Summit in which country?",
        "options": [
            "France  ",
            "United States  ",
            "Germany  ",
            "United Kingdom "
        ],
        "answer": "France  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was honoured with the Pravasi Bharatiya Samman Award 2025 for contributions to healthcare and community welfare?",
        "options": [
            "Dr. Rajesh Malhotra ",
            "Dr Ayesha Siddiqui ",
            "Dr Syed Anwar Khursheed ",
            "Dr. Manoj Reddy "
        ],
        "answer": "Dr Syed Anwar Khursheed ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the 6th and final Scorpene-class submarine delivered to the Indian Navy under Project P-75?",
        "options": [
            "Vaghsheer ",
            "Vagir ",
            "Vela ",
            "Karanj "
        ],
        "answer": "Vaghsheer ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank partnered with Bajaj Broking to offer a unified 3-in-1 account integrating banking, broking, and investment services?",
        "options": [
            "HDFC Bank ",
            "ICICI Bank ",
            "Tamilnad Mercantile Bank ",
            "Axis Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Tamilnad Mercantile Bank ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has become the first state in India to abolish its longstanding tendering system?",
        "options": [
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Kerala  ",
            "Tamil Nadu "
        ],
        "answer": "Uttar Pradesh  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is India's first credit rating agency?",
        "options": [
            "CRISIL ",
            "ICRA ",
            "CARE ",
            "SMERA "
        ],
        "answer": "CRISIL ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2713 CRISIL (Credit Rating Information Services of India Limited) is a global analytics company that provides ratings, research, risk, and policy advisory services. \u2713 It was established in 1987 and is headquartered in Mumbai, India.  Follow us: Official Site, Telegram, Facebook, Instagram, Youtube 183  \u2713 CRISIL is India's leading ratings agency and also a leading provider of high-end research to the world's largest banks and leading corporations. Q. Credit Rating Agencies in India is regulated by which of the following entities?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Corporate Affairs ",
            "Ministry of Finance ",
            "Securities and Exchange Board of India  ",
            "Reserve Bank of India "
        ],
        "answer": "Securities and Exchange Board of India  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Consumer firm its rebranding of \u2018Fair and Handsome\u2019 to \u2018Smart and Handsome?",
        "options": [
            "Emami ",
            "Godrej ",
            "Patanjali ",
            "Britannia Industries "
        ],
        "answer": "Emami ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been roped in as the International Event Ambassador for the 20th edition of the Tata Mumbai Marathon?",
        "options": [
            "Fred Kerley ",
            "Akani Simbine ",
            "Noah Lyles ",
            "Mo Farah "
        ],
        "answer": "Mo Farah ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been awarded the prestigious India Fellowship of the Indian National Science Academy (INS",
        "options": [
            "for 2025? ",
            "Dr. Krishna Ella ",
            "Dr. Lekh Raj Juneja ",
            "Dr. Sharmila Ford ",
            "Dr. Sharad Lakhanpal "
        ],
        "answer": "for 2025? ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which food delivery aggregator has launched a new standalone app called \u201cPyng\u201d to enter the professional services marketplace?",
        "options": [
            "Zomato ",
            "Swiggy ",
            "KFC ",
            "Domino's Pizza "
        ],
        "answer": "Swiggy ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Food aggregator platform has signed a memorandum of understanding (MoU) with Robin Hood Army, an NGO focused on fighting hunger through surplus food distribution?",
        "options": [
            "Zomato ",
            "Swiggy ",
            "EatSure ",
            "Domino's Pizza "
        ],
        "answer": "Swiggy ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the new food delivery app launched by Swiggy, It is a 15-minute food delivery app offering quick snacks and meals, similar to Zepto\u2019s Zepto Cafe?",
        "options": [
            "Snacc by Swiggy ",
            "Swiggy Snack ",
            "Swiggy Dash ",
            "Swiggy Quick "
        ],
        "answer": "Snacc by Swiggy ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements with respect to \u201ceBkray\u201d:   1. It was launched by Indian Banks Association (IB",
        "options": [
            "2. \u201ceBkray\u201d platform enables the online auction of the attached assets transparently and cleanly for ",
            "1 only  ",
            "2 only  ",
            "Both 1 and 2  ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "2 only  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to Bima Sugam, consider the following statements:  1.It aims to simplify the process of purchasing insurance for consumers.    2.It is a government-owned insurance company.  3.Bima Sugam will fulfill all insurance needs, encompassing life, health, and general insurance, such as motor and travel coverage.  Which of the statements given above are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 and 2 only ",
            "2 and 3 only ",
            "1 and 3 only ",
            "1, 2 and 3 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 and 3 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institution/organisation releases the World Economic Situation and Prospects report?",
        "options": [
            "United Nations ",
            "UNESCO  ",
            "WEF ",
            "UNDP "
        ],
        "answer": "United Nations ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the first estimate of the National Statistical Office, the expected growth rate of the Indian economy in 2024-25 is to be?",
        "options": [
            "6.6% ",
            "6.4% ",
            "6.8% ",
            "6.2% "
        ],
        "answer": "6.4% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government has set a target of installation of 1000 MW of solar plants through women self-help groups (SHG)?",
        "options": [
            "Bihar  ",
            "Jharkhand  ",
            "Telangana  ",
            "Tamil Nadu "
        ],
        "answer": "Telangana  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government has launched the Indira Mahila Shakti Scheme to empower the women of the state through women self help groups?",
        "options": [
            "Kerala  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Uttarakhand  ",
            "Telangana "
        ],
        "answer": "Telangana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is helping India in constructing a nuclear power plant in Kudankulam, Tamil Nadu?",
        "options": [
            "China ",
            "Russia  ",
            "United States  ",
            "Israel "
        ],
        "answer": "Russia  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the INS Vaghsheer:  1. It is the sixth submarine belongs to Kalvari-class submarines for the Indian Navy.  2. It consists of indigenously developed systems like internal communication network and the Ku-Band SATCOM system.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to Silver Notice, consider the following:  1. It is the latest addition to Interpol\u2019s suite of colour-coded alerts.  2. It allows participating nations to request information on assets linked to criminal activities such as fraud and corruption.  3. India is not a part of this new initiative of Interpol.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 and 2 only ",
            "2 and 3 only ",
            "1 and 3 only  ",
            "1, 2 and 3 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 and 2 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The National Youth Day is organized every year to commemorate the birth anniversary of which Indian leader?",
        "options": [
            "Subhas Chandra Bose ",
            "Swami Vivekananda ",
            "Bhagat Singh ",
            "A.P.J. Abdul Kalam "
        ],
        "answer": "Swami Vivekananda ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Project Veer Gatha:  1. It aims to raise awareness of Gallantry awardees\u2019 acts of bravery and the life stories of these heroes.  2. It is an initiative of the union Ministry of Home Affairs.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the length of the Z-Morh Tunnel or Sonmarg Tunnel in Kashmir?",
        "options": [
            "6.5 km ",
            "9.5 km ",
            "8.5 km ",
            "7.5 km "
        ],
        "answer": "6.5 km ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government launched the Swami Vivekanand Yuva Shakti Mission on 12 January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Himachal Pradesh  ",
            "Uttarakhand "
        ],
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where has the world\u2019s largest 3-D rangoli depicting Swami Vivekananda been inaugurated?",
        "options": [
            "Lucknow  ",
            "Hyderabad  ",
            "Bhopal  ",
            "Patna "
        ],
        "answer": "Bhopal  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]